

BIPIN MV

Front End Engineer

+91 9895051128

bipinmv.netlify.app

in linkedin.com/in/bipin-mv

github.com/bipinmv

SUMMARY

Innovative Front End Developer with 2+ years of experience. Dedicated to creating and optimising interactive, user-friendly, feature rich and pixel perfect web applications. Exposure to Front-end & Back-end web development and Progressive Web Application (PWA) development

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES



ACHIEVEMENTS

- Passed LinkedIn assessment for JavaScript, React.js and CSS.
- Achieved Inquisitive award from current organization
- Earned five star Gold badge for Python on HackerRank.
- CutShort certified JavaScript Advanced.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications
Bharathiar University Coimbatore
2018 – 2020 • 81.3%

Bachelor of Computer ApplicationsPilathara Co-operative Arts & Science College 2015 – 2018 • 69%

XII CPNM GHSS Mathamangalam 2013 – 2015 • 87.8%

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UI Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

Prevalent Al

Kochi

- Achieved KaPAI (Great Work) Inquisitive Award
- Completely owned a project
- Was responsible for developing the project from zero to production
- Migrated to TypeScript, improved the performance by 3x, mentored juniors

Associate Software Engineer

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Caparizon

Kochi

- Full Stack Developer (React.js and Node.js)
- Responsible for creating applications from scratch
- Wearing multiple hats as the company strength is small

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Analytical Dashboard & Data visualization

Front-end Developer for building analytical dashboards and visualizations using React and HighCharts. Was also responsible for building middleware using Express.js to power the dashboard with data.

Ticket Booking System

Full Stack Developer for building user interface and APIs using React.js and Express.js for a travel agency from scratch. Used PostgreSQL as database management system.

PoC Project for Insurance Company

Full Stack Developer responsible for developing complete PoC project using React.js and Express.js for an insurance company.

ACADEMIC/WEEKEND PROJECTS

Explore more projects on bipinmv.netlify.app/projects